

# Mikolaj Semeniuk

Email: m.semeniuk@icloud.com Telephone: +48 533 838 844 Github: https://github.com/mikolajsemeniuk/ StackOverflow: https://stackoverflow.com/users/

13947931/mikolaj-semeniuk

#### **Skills**

- Very good knowledge of Java version 8 and its data structures, including Optional, Streams and Regex expressions
- Very good knowledge of Spring Framework and Spring Security
- Very good command of C# version 5.0 and its data structures, inter alia, structures IEnumerable, ICollection, OneOf, LINQ, await/async, Regex and Reflection
- Very good command of .NET framework and Entity Framework, Migrations, Identity Server 4 and MassTransit
- Very good knowledge of Python version **3.7**, especially in data analysis and building models to perform predictions, classification, learning about data structure, data tagging, generating synthetic data using Sklearn, Pytorch, Tensorflow and Keras
- Very good knowledge of **Docker** and **Kubernetes**
- Very good knowledge of Linux and **Bash** (I use Linux every day)
- Very good knowledge of Windows **Forms**
- Very good knowledge of VueJS and AngularJS frameworks, frontend application state management, dynamic data sending, displaying API requests
- Very good knowledge of languages such as NodeJS, GoLang and **ExpressJS** and **Go-GIN**frameworks
- Very good knowledge of the practices of writing Clean Code Uncle Bob's, SOLID principles, DDD, TDD and knowledge of design patterns such as CQRS, CQS, MVC, Fabric
- Very good knowledge of relational databases such as: SQL Server, MySQL, PostgresSQL
- databases such as: MongoDB, Redis, poor Apache Cassandra

Very good knowledge of non-relational

- Ability to write unit tests and tests using the **Selenium** framework
- Very good command of the English language
- Very good knowledge of of environments such as: Visual Studio, Intellij, Visual Studio Code, Google Colab, Jupyter notebook oraz Conda

I am currently an extramural 3rd year student in **Data Science**. I have almost **three** years of experience in developing web applications mainly in languages such as Java and C # and data analysis using Python.

In my spare time I read books about data analysis, especially about unsupervised learning, and I learn new languages and upload projects to GitHuba, Google Colab, I also participate in StackOverflow

## **Experience**

### **Ernst & Young**

2021.09-

2020.11-

2020.05

2020.05-

I was employed as a junior analyst, but the scope of my duties varied depending on the projects to which I was assigned. Below are the projects and responsibilities.

Implementation of new functionalities and modernization of the internal 2021.01 portal of the British insurer. I was responsible for:

- Adding new functionalities contained on the portal: **Jira** and Confluence in accordance with the Scrum methodology
- Communicating with Business Analysts and Scrum Master from Great Britain in English
- Implementation of API endpoints using Spring Web compatible with the Controller, Service, Repository pattern
- Implementing user rights and roles and generating authentication tokens using OAuth2 and Spring Security
- Configuration of communication between **micro services** using RabbitMQ
- Implementation of writes and reads to the **SQL Server** relational database
- Sending and receiving SOAP and REST requests
- Upload files using requests
- Creating new branches, resolving merge conflicts and adding changes to the repository via Git version control versions, and Azure Dev Ops
- Writing unit tests
- Testing API with Postman, Insomnii and Swagger
- Writing and reading technical documentation

Data analysis for EY internal EY business process recognition tool. I was 2020.12-2020.11 responsible for:

- Cleaning and preparation of collected data
- Data analysis using python 3.7, sklearn, pandas, numpy, matplotib and **seaborn**
- Feature detection with **sklearn** algorithms such as **PCA**, **K-means** and **K Nearest Neighbors**
- Building data structure learning models using Pytorch and tensorflow such as Autoencoders

portal of the company from the United States dealing with the production of prostheses. I was responsible for: Adding new functionalities contained on the portal: Jira and Confluence

Implementation of new functionalities and modernization of the internal

- in accordance with the **Scrum** methodology Communicating with Business Analysts and Scrum Master from the
- **United States in English**
- Implementation of API endpoints using Asp Net Core Mvc compatible with the **Controller, Service, IService** pattern
- Implementing user rights and roles and generating authentication tokens using OAuth2 and Asp Net Identity and Identity Server 4
- Communication configuration between microservices using RabbitMQ and **MassTransit**
- Implementation of writes and reads to the SQL Server relational database and Redis NoSQL database
- Sending and receiving GRAPHQL requests using the Hot Chocolate framework and **REST** requests
- Upload files using requests
- Creating new branches, resolving merge conflicts and adding changes to the repository via **Git** version control versions, and **Azure Dev Ops**
- Testing API with Postman, Insomnii and Swagger Writing and reading technical documentation

Writing unit tests with xUnit and Moq

from Poznań using the NodeJS language and the Express is framework. I 2020.02 was responsible for:

Adding new functionalities in accordance with the Scrum methodology

Implementation of an internal invoice settlement portal for a company

- Communicating with client and Scrum Master File validation in terms of business logic
- Uploading, reading and saving a large number of files (mainly excel
- files) on the server Sending emails to customers who are in arrears with payment of their
- debts Testing API with Postman, Insomnii and Swagger
- Writes and reads to the PostgresSQL relational database
- Creating new branches, resolving merge conflicts and adding changes to the repository via Git version control versions, and GitLab
- LastLevel

Implementation of new functionalities on the front and backend side in 2019.11-2019.02 online stores and blogs as well as data analysis for these portals. I was responsible for:

I worked as a full-stack developer using technologies such as PHP with Laravel

framework and JavaScript with frameworks, AngularJS and VueJS

compatible with the MVC pattern

- Maintaining application state with Vue Store and Angular NGRX
  - Sending REST requests using Vue Axios and Angular HttpClient to the backend
  - using Electron and Apache Cordova Dynamic display of backend data

Generating mobile and desktop applications from JavaScript code

- Implementation of new artwork using VueJS and AngularJS, and bootstrap, material, tailwind css frameworks and SCSS
- Implementing user rights and roles and generating authentication tokens

• Implementation of **API** endpoints using the **Laravel** framework

- using Laravel Passport • Implementation of writes and reads to the **MySQL** referential database
- Sending emails to users
- Testing API with Postman, Insomnii and Swagger

 Creating new branches, resolving merge conflicts and adding changes to the repository via Git version control versions, and GitLab, and

Logistic Regression, Random Forests, K- Means, K Nearest **Neighbors** from **Sklearn** 

Data analysis using the Python language and algorithms: PCA,

RedMine

**Education** 

Present-

**Warsaw School of Computer Science** 

2019.10 extramural mode, specializing in Data Science. I am currently in my third year and I am starting an engineering thesis about generating synthetic data by the Deep Belief Network model (Deep Belief Network)

In 2019, I started my studies at the Warsaw School of Computer Science in